Guide to the Louis Walinsky papers, 1978-1992.
Walinsky, Louis papers, 1978-1992
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Louis Walinsky papers, 1978-1992.
4874
Louis Joseph, Walinsky 1908-
5.0 cubic ft.
Notes, letters, manuscripts, clippings, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Daily records kept during six years of service as chief resident economic advisor to the Burmese government, 1953-1958, noting the progress and difficulties encountered in Burma's efforts to achieve accelerated economic development, and weekly letters during the same period to Robert Nathan, the head of the economic consulting firm Louis Walinsky and his team represented, summarizing and assessing the recorded events. Additionally, correspondence, reports, articles, publications, and other materials relating to Burma and Burmese economic and political affairs, including intermittent correspondence and memos with and for U Nu.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Economic consultant.
Louis Walinsky was born in London in 1908, the son of Russian âemigrâe parents, and came to the United States in 1912. In 1929 he graduated from Cornell University, where he majored in economics under Sumner Slichter and Herbert Joseph Davenport, and went on to do graduate work at the University of Berlin, CCNY, and the New School. He taught economics in New York City from 1930-1943; served as an economic consultant for the War Production Board from 1943-47; as Director of the World ORT Union's network of vocational training schools for liberated Jews in the D.P. camps of Germany, and Secretary-General from 1947-49; as vice president of Robert Nathan Associates from 1950-1963; and as an economic consultant in Washington and Cohasset, Mass. from 1963.
Additionally, he was executive secretary of the Combined Pulp and Paper Commission of the Combined Raw Materials Board, 1944-45; director of the Office of Economic Review and Analysis of the Civilian Production Administration, 1946-47; member and/or leader of economic missions to Korea, Afghanistan, El Salvador, Brazil, East Africa, Israel, Iran, India, Bolivia, Venezuela, Newfoundland, Papua New Guinea, and Puerto Rico; chief resident economic advisor to the Government of Burma, 1953-58; special advisor to the Asia Dept. of the World Bank, 1971-72; and consultant to OECD, 1978. He is the author of numerous books and articles, particularly on international economic development. In 1990, he funded "The Memorial Fund in Economics in Honor of Professor Herbert Joseph Davenport."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Daily records kept during six years of service as chief resident economic advisor to the Burmese government, 1953-1958, noting the progress and difficulties encountered in Burma's efforts to achieve accelerated economic development, and weekly letters during the same period to Robert Nathan, the head of the economic consulting firm Louis Walinsky and his team represented, summarizing and assessing the recorded events. Additionally, correspondence, reports, articles, publications, and other materials relating to Burma and Burmese economic and political affairs, including intermittent correspondence and memos with and for U Nu.
Correspondents and commentators on the Burmese question include Joe Silverstein, Chao-Tzang Yawnghwe, U Aung, and David Doan.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Walinsky, Louis Joseph,1908-; Doan, David.; Silverstein, Joe.; Yawnghwe, Chao-Tzang.; ®Oçn°,; CRDB (Organization).; United States.Congress.House.Committee on Foreign Affairs.
Places:
Burma--Politics and government.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Files labeled COPIES may not contain a complete set of duplications of the ORIGINALS folders. It may also be possible that the COPIES folders contain items that are not in the ORIGINALS folders.
CONTAINER LIST
- News Articles about Burma, 1947 - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- News Articles about Burma, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- News Articles about Burma, January - August 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- News Articles about Burma, July - December 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- News Articles about Burma, January - March 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- News Articles about Burma, April - December 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- News Articles about Burma, January - April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- News Articles about Burma, May - December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- News Articles about Burma, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- News Articles about Burma, 1992 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- News Articles about Burma, 1995 - 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- News Articles about Burma, 1997 - 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- News Articles about Burma, 1999 - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Robert R. Nathan 1958 Trip (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Joe Silverstein, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Tin Maung Win, 1987 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chao-Tzang Yawnghwe (Eugene Thaik), 1988 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- David B. Doan, 1988 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- U Kyaw Win and The Burma Bulletin, 1988 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- 1989 Hearing Solarz and U.S. House Sub Committee (Box 1, Folder 20)
- W. Law Yone, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- U Aung, 1989 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Chao-Tzang Yawnghwe: Thesis, April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Journal of Democracy, Fall 1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Harn Yawng Hwe and The Burma Alert, 1990 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- State of Fear: Censorship in Burma, December 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Burma Press, December 1991 - May 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Southeast Asia Articles, May - July 1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Burma and the United Nations, 1992 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Utne Reader, July/August 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Articles, Notes, Correspondence, 1990 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Lectures, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Burma Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles and Letters, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Articles, November 1991 - April 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Reports and Articles, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Burma Review and Correspondence, December 1991 - January 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Articles, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Articles on Burmese Human Rights, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - ORIGINALS, September - December 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - COPIES, September - December 1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - ORIGINALS, January - December 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - COPIES, January - December 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - ORIGINALS, January - December 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - COPIES, January - December 1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - ORIGINALS, January - October 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - COPIES, January - August 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - ORIGINALS, 1957 - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Louis Walinsky letters to Bob Nathan - COPIES, 1957 - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - ORIGINALS, September 1953 - December 1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - COPIES, September 1953 - December 1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - ORIGINALS, January - December 1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - ORIGINALS, January - December 1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - COPIES, January 1955 - December 1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - ORIGINALS, March - December 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - COPIES, March - July 1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - ORIGINALS, January - December 1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Bob Nathan letters to Louis Walinsky - COPIES, January 1958 - April 1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Interviews, Notes for Book - ORIGINALS, January 1959 - May 1961 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, Interviews, Notes for Book - COPIES, January 1959 - May 1961 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence to Louis Walinsky, 1991 - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Louis Walinsky: Messages, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, September - December 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, March - April 1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, May - June 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, July - September 1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, October - December 1954 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, January - March 1955 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, April - June 1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, July - September 1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, November - December 1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, January - March 1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, April - June 1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, July - September 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, October - December 1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, January - March 1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, April - June 1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, July - August 1957 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, November - December 1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, January - March 1958 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, April - June 1958 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, July - September 1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, October - December 1958 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Daily Records - ORIGINALS, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Letters to Louis Walinsky, 1953 - 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Letters from Louis Walinsky, 1956 - 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Louis Walinsky: Notes and Drafts, 1958 - 1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Louis Walinsky and U Nu: Letters, Articles, Opinions, 1957 - 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Uprising: Correspondence and Articles, 1968 - 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1970 - 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1975 - 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Balwant Singh: letters to Louis Walinsky; letters from Louis Walinsky regarding Singh, 1979 - 1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1982 - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Louis Walinsky: copies of letters, notes, memorandums, 1991 - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Letters to Louis Walinsky, 1991 - 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Letters from Louis Walinsky, 1991 - 2001 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1994 - 2000 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Letters to Bob Helvey, 1994 - 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Letters to Louis Walinsky, 1999 - 2001 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Democracy Clippings and Papers on Burma, 1990 - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Government in Exile, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Ed Broadbent: International Centre for Human Rights and Democratic Development (ICHRDD), April - October 1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma (NCGUB): Agenda/Minutes and 1,000 Comrades, September 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Solarz Hearing, October 18, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Nobel Prize Appeal Press Conference (Dr. Sein Win), November 14, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Louis Walinsky: views and bio-data, 1991 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Bob Helvey: Articles, Reports, Correspondence, December 1992 - December 1993 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Free Suu Kyi, Free Burma by David Arnott, May 1992 and June 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Burma Booklets: Mya Yadana; Freedom Review; Burma's Revolution of the Spirit, 1992 - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- U.S.-Burma Conference, June 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- U.S. House Foreign Affairs Committee: Subcommittee on Asia/Pacific, June 29, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- News Articles Regarding the U.S. and Burma, July 1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Burma Pamphlets, 1998 - 1999 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Sambuddhe Gatha, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Photographs, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Burma Pamphlets, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Burma Pamphlets, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- News Articles from Time, The New York Times, The Atlantic Review and Pacific Affairs, 1954 and 1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- U Thant: letters to U Thant and articles about U Thant, 1954-1955 and 1957 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- U Nu: articles and correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Raschid and Kyaw Nyein: notes, correspondence, minutes, 1956, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- "See It Now": Louis Walinsky and Edward Murrow, November 4, 1956 and February 3, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- U Nu: articles, correspondence, notes, etc., 1959-1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Newspaper Articles and Notes for Walinsky Articles, 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Burma Pamphlets, 1960-1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Louis Walinsky Writings, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Yawnghwe: articles, correspondence, bio-data, 1965-1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Bo Setkya (Aung Than): articles, correspondence, notes, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Ne Win's U.S. Visit, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- U Nu Papers, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- 1969 Oil Contract, September - November 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Walinsky and the 1970 Revolt, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Kyaw Win and others: articles, correspondence, The Burma Bulletin, 1973-1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Burmese Book, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Union of Burma Trade Agreements, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Burmese Trade Agreements, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Burmese Trade Agreements, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Maung Nu Letters to General Ne Win, 1963-1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1956-1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Schooling in the Service of Socialist Authoritarianism: Education and Political Socialization in Burma During the Socialist Era (1962-88) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- The Burma Review, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- The Burma Review, 1991 - 1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- The Burma Bulletin, 1977; 1991 - 1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Asia Watch: A Division of Human Rights Watch, 1992 - 1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- The Burma Alert by Associates to Develop Democratic Burma, 1992 - 1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- The Burma Alert by Associates to Develop Democratic Burma, 1996 - 1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Threshold, January - May 1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- The Voice of Burma, 1996 - 1997 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Boycott Burma: Master Copies, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Free Burma Listserve, September 1995 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Free Burma Listserve, October 1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Free Burma Listserve, November - December 1995 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Free Burma Listserve, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Burma Advocacy Groups, 1993 - 2000 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- The Committee for the Restoration of Democracy in Burma (CRDB): "The First Five Years: After SLORC What?" by Louis Walinsky, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 15)
- The Committee for the Restoration of Democracy in Burma (CRDB) I, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- The Committee for the Restoration of Democracy in Burma (CRDB) II, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- The Committee for the Restoration of Democracy in Burma (CRDB) III, 1992 - 2001 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- The Institute for Community and Institutional Development (ICID), 1998 - 2001 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- FBC: Overview Booklet, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- FBC: Notes and Messages, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- FBC: Press Packet I, November 1996 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- FBC: Press Packet II, November 1996 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- FBC: Contact Information, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- FBC: News Articles on FBC and Burma, 1994 - 1998 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- FBC: News Stories Mentioning FBC, October 1995 - February 1999 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- FBC: News Stories Mentioning FBC, May - December 1996 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- FBC: News Stories Mentioning FBC, January 1997 - March 1998 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Resident Americans and Dependents in Burma, October 1, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Louis Walinsky Personal 20th Century Fund, 1960 - 1961 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- News from the 20th Century Fund, January 18, 1960 and July 16, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- The Asia Society, 1963 - 1966 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Georgetown Seminar, May 8, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- The Population of Burma by M. Ismael Khin Maung, April 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- U Nu and Daw Mya Yee Tour, March - October 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Sein Win Visit: Suggested Program, June 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Burma Action Meeting I, November 15-17, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Burma Action Meeting II, November 15-17, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- N.E.D. (National Endowment for Democracy): Submission, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- N.E.D. (National Endowment for Democracy): Helvey Project, June - December 1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- N.E.D. (National Endowment for Democracy): Follow on Project/Peace Institute, August 1992 - February 1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Application for Recognition of Exemption; Income and Expenses, 1992 - 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Albert Einstein Grant, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- N.E.D. (National Endowment for Democracy): Final Report, February 22, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Statement of Miriam Marshall Segal, June 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Statement by U Ohn Gyaw, October 1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- The 1598-99 Siege of Pegu and the Expansion of Arakanese Imperial Power into Lower Burma by Michael W. Charney, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- U.S. Congress and Burma, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Final Report: Political Defiance Instruction for the Democratic Voice of Burma Staff, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- UNOCAL: Yadana Project and Executive Summary, November 1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Amnesty International: Burma, 1995 - 1996 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Burma: Pamphlets and Magazines, 1995 - 1998 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Human Rights Watch: Burma, 1995, 1997, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Burma: Booklets, 1995 - 2001 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- U.S. Senate Banking Committee, May 22, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Guns, Boats and Shipbuilding: Continuity and Change in Myanma Ship Structure and River Warfare in the Early Modern Era by Michael W. Charney, October 25, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Responsibility of Western Companies in Promoting Human Rights by Professor A. Gelpern, December 14, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Setting the Agenda: U.S. State and Local Laws on Human Rights by H. Bradley Myers, December 16, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- News Articles about Burma, 1996 - 1997 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Amnesty International: Burma, 1996 - 2001 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Economic Development of Burma, May 1997 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Mandalay Directory, 1997 - 1998 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- Interview with Aung San Suu Ky, June 1999 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Academic Articles on Burma, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Burma: Asia's Richest Poor Country by Joel L. Swerdlow, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 37)
- The Burma Road: A Book Prospect by Wendy Law-Yone (Box 10, Folder 38)
- From Dictatorship to Democracy by Gene Sharp, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Crude Investment by Jensine Larsen, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 40)
- The Aphorisms of Arnold, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Burma (in Burmese), n.d. (Box 10, Folder 42)
- For Burma Scrap Book I, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 43)
- For Burma Scrap Book II, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 44)
- National Geographic, October 1931 and November 1940 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- His Excellency the Governor's Consultative Committee: Financial Year, 1943 - 1944 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Robert R. Nathan Associates, Inc. Confidential File, 1953 - 1957 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Index of Reports prepared by Robert R. Nathan Associates, Inc., 1953 - 1959 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Lectures: Economic Planning; Importance of Modern Accounting in a Socialist State, 1953 and 1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- List of Mimeographed Documents prepared by Robert R. Nathan Associates, Inc., September 1953 - November 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Robert Nathan's Diary, February - March 1954 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Address by the Honorable Prime Minister, September 28, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Testimony of Robert Nathan, November 15, 1955 and January 31, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Burma Chamber of Commerce: Chairman's Review of the Year 1955, January 21, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- "Nathan Plan to Make Food Surplus an Asset to World" by David C. Williams, May 5, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Forms and Problems of Organization and Administration in Public and Semi-Public Enterprises, June 27, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- U Win Speech: Burma's Economic Development and U.S. Participation, October 4, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Speech by Prime Minister, October 5, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- "Burma's Foreign Policy, 1948 - 1956" by Frank Trager, November 1956 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Appendix A: Production, Exports, Prices and Exchange Rates, November 5, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Some Aspects of Economic Development (Multiple Drafts), December 5, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Review of the Economy for 1956, February 1957 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Salient Points of Weakness of New State Industrial Ventures, June 17, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Measure to Improve Efficiency, Performance and Management in State-Owned Enterprises, June 17, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Speech by the Prime Minister: The National Economy and the Four Year Plan, August 2, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Louis Walinsky letters to U Mo Myit (Prime Minister's Secretary of Planning), November 1957 - October 1958 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- The Essence of Marxist Theory, January 16, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- The Nation: U Nu Repudiates Marxism as Basic Philosophy of AFPFL; U Ba Swe Threatens to Fight Anyone Who Splits League, January 30, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Comments on the Retrenchment Programme, April 25, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Comments on the Petition (undated) of the All-Burma Indian Congress to the Honorable Prime Minister, June 18, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Pricing Policy for Public and Government Enterprises, August 6-8, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Newspaper Articles, September 1958 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- "The Political Split in Burma" by Frank Trager, October 1958 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- The Nation: Letter to the Editor, October 7, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Robert R. Nathan Associates on Burma's Public Administration, November 1958 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Policies Governing Investment and Operation of Industrial Enterprises, November 1, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- What Should Be Done About the Cost of Living?, November 7, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Economic Statistics, December 16, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Thirteen Final Papers by Robert R. Natian Associates, Inc., January 31, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 35)
- The Spirit of Burmese Politics by Lucian W. Pye, April 1959 (Box 11, Folder 36)
- Notes for The Economic Development of Burma, 1960 - 1962 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Letters to Louis Walinsky regarding The Economic Development of Burma, 1960 - 1962 (Box 11, Folder 38)
- The Economic Development of Burma - Book Reviews and News Articles, 1960 - 1964 (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Silent Crisis in Burma by Louis Walinsky, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- Burma AID Program, July 1965 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- National Geographic, 1971 and 1974 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- The Burmese Way of Change by Richard Butwell, December 1976 (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Notes: Key Current Memoranda (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Honorable Finance Minister's Speech, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 45)
- Chairman's Speech to the Chamber of Commerce, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 46)
- Daily Records - COPIES, September - December 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Daily Records - COPIES, March - April 1954 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Daily Records - COPIES, May - June 1954 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Daily Records - COPIES, July - September 1954 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Daily Records - COPIES, October - December 1954 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Daily Records - COPIES, January - March 1955 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Daily Records - COPIES, April - June 1955 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Daily Records - COPIES, July - September 1955 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Daily Records - COPIES, November - December 1955 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Daily Records - COPIES, January - March 1956 (Box 12, Folder 10)